TheChaosLegion
～♪
I want to shine on you, and always like that dazzling sun.
I will defend you from all the darkness.
（バルサ）ハァ ハァ
ハァ ハァ…
This is the truth from my heart.
If only our hearts could connect, I could get you to believe me.
Even if you can't see it now, don't lose it.
（無宿人）うわっ！ 何だよ
Your kindness won't be in vain.
You'll be carried aloft by the wind to somewhere that isn't here.
You'll cross the sea and cross time, and I know you'll blossom one day.
Whatever the day, I'll be there for you.
I hope I can watch over you like the sun for all time.
This is the truth from my heart.
Moribito Guardian of the Spirit
Is that you, Balsa?
（タンダ）バルサか？
遅かったな
You sure took your time.
We were worried that you'd been
captured by those people from the palace.
宮の者に捕まったんじゃないかと
心配したぞ
Where's Chagum?
（バルサ）チャグムは？
（トロガイ）ここにおる
Right here.
事の子細は聞いた
I've heard the particulars
of what happened.
トウミ村に
直行するほかないね
We have no choice but to head
straight for Toumi village, then?
はい
（トロガイ）では急ごう
Yes.
Then let's hurry.
（チャグム）バルサ
Balsa.
I want to go back to the palace and
find out what happened to my brother.
俺は一度 宮に戻って
兄上のことを詳しく知りたい
本当に兄上が
亡くなったというのなら 俺は…
If it turns out that
he truly is dead, then I...
ダメだ お前を宮に
帰すことはできない
No. I can't allow you
to go back to the palace.
I'll explain why later.
（バルサ）訳はあとで話す
それに今は
追っ手をまくことが先だ
Besides, the first thing we need
to do is to shake our pursuers!
Episode 18
The Ancient Village
How did the prince appear to you?
（モン）それで 皇子のご様子は？
（シュガ）すっかり
お変わりになられていた
His appearance
had utterly changed.
一見したところ 街の子供と
見分けがつかぬほどに
To the extent that he would pass for
any child of the city at first glance...
He must have disguised
himself to prevent...
（モン）宮の人間に見つかるまいと
あえて身をやつしていたのでしょう
...residents of the
palace from finding him.
However...
（シュガ）ただ…
以前と変わらず―
One thing remained unchanged.
He seemed as lively and sound as ever.
はつらつとした
健やかな お顔をしておられた
I heard what happened
from Master Shuga.
（モン）話はシュガ様から聞いた
で どうだった？
Did you have any luck?
（ジン）扇(おうぎ)の下(しも)を
探し回りましたが…
No, I searched all
over Ogi no Shimo.
I'm sorry. I have been
of no use whatsoever.
すまぬ 私が
ふがいないばかりに…
I am simply thankful that we have
confirmed that he is alive and well.
まずは ご無事を
確認できただけでも何よりです
What is most important now is that
we do not fail in our next attempt.
大切なのは次の一手を
打ち漏らさぬこと
Zen.
ゼン
（ゼン）はっ！
Sir.
これは？
What's this?
頼まれ屋が短槍(たんそう)使いのところに
届けた荷物です
The goods that the errand runner
delivered to the spear-wielder.
She was preparing
to set out on a journey?
（シュガ）旅支度を
していたということか？
But from what I saw...
しかし 私が見たかぎり
皇子は ほんの数刻前まで―
...the prince didn't seem to have
any clue until just a few hours before...
再び追われる身になるとは
ついぞ知らぬといった感じだったが
...that he was about
to go on the run again.
（モン）恐らく短槍使いは
シュガ様と遭遇する前から―
It appears that the spear-wielder
was planning to set out for somewhere...
どこかに出かけようとしていたのだと
思われます
...even before she
bumped into you, Master Shuga.
Fortunately, the contents of this pack
will allow us to deduce her destination.
おかげで行き先を
この荷物から探ることができます
（シュガ）なるほど
I see.
この量からすると
皇子と２人で３日分
Judging from these quantities, she was
planning a three-day trip with the prince.
This is not enough to cross
the Misty Blue Mountains.
これでは青霧(あおぎり)を
越えることは かなわない
うむ
そこで考えられるのは―
From this, we can deduce
that they will either go south...
都南街道(となんかいどう)を下るか
東の山岳地帯に入るかだ
...on the Tonan highway or they'll enter
the mountainous region to the east.
There is no chance that they
will go to Rota or Sangal?
（シュガ）ロタやサンガルの
可能性はないのか？
It's hard to believe that they would
make for the border carrying provisions.
（モン）食料を持って
国境を目指すとは考えにくい
There are any number
of inns along the way.
途中に いくつも
宿場がございます
I see.
なるほど ではまず
都南街道への関門に 伝令を走らせよう
In that case, I shall start by dispatching
runners to the Tonan highway barrier.
さすれば 海岸部までの一本道
皇子を見つけ出すのは たやすい
That will make it a simple
matter to find the prince...
...on the single road
leading to the coast.
Which leaves the
mountains to the east.
あとは東の山間部だな
（モン）はい
Yes.
Now why would the
bodyguard travel east?
女用心棒が
東に向かう理由は何だ？
あそこは
青霧ほどの標高はないが―
They aren't as high
as the Misty Blues...
原生林に覆われた
山々が連なる未踏の地
...but the area is largely unexplored
and covered with primeval forests.
I can't think of anything there besides
a handful of Yakoo settlements.
せいぜいヤクーの集落が
点在しているだけだぞ
That's it! The Yakoo!
そうか ヤクーか！
（モン）ん…
When I met the bodyguard, I was
perplexed by her words and actions.
女用心棒と会って
その言動を不思議に思っていたのだ
She seemed to know
even more about...
ヤツはチャグム皇子に宿った
精霊について―
...the spirit within
Prince Chagum than I do.
私よりも詳しく
事情を知っている気配があった
カンバル人であるあの女が
なぜと思ったが―
I wondered how someone
from Kanbal could know so much.
She must have gained this
knowledge from the Yakoo.
恐らくヤクーより
知識を得たからだ
I see.
なるほど
That would also explain the
mud dolls we found on the valley floor...
だとしたら青霧の谷で見つかった
皇子と短槍使いの身代わりが―
...instead of the prince and her
up in the Misty Blue Mountains.
泥人形であったことにも
合点がいく
（ゼン）初めて あの女と剣を交えた
棚田の先にも―
There is a Yakoo settlement called
Yashiro village beyond the terrace fields...
...where we first
crossed swords with her.
ヤシロ村という集落があります
頼まれ屋以外にも
ヤクーの仲間がいたということか
So she had a Yakoo accomplice
in addition to the errand runner...
だが ヤシロ辺りなら
旅支度などは不要
Perhaps, but a trip to Yashiro
wouldn't call for such preparations.
仮に その奥の集落に向かう
腹積もりだったとして―
And even if they intended to travel to
a settlement farther off in that direction...
我らに見つかった以上―
...I doubt they would travel to their initial
destination now that we've located them.
当初の目的地へ向かうとは
思えませんが？
もちろん その可能性も考え―
I will keep that possibility
in mind, of course.
I will have them step up surveillance
on the Sangal and Rota barriers.
サンガルやロタへの
関門の監視は強化させる
（モン）シュガ様
ここは今すぐ兵を率い―
Master Shuga, perhaps it would be
wise to summon troops right away...
すべての街道
さらには光扇京(こうせんきょう)全域を―
...to check every highway, as well as
search Kosenkyo from top to bottom.
くまなく調べるべきでは
ありませんか？
That would take far too long.
それでは あまりに
時間が かかりすぎる
それにな モン
And one other thing, Mon.
私はどうも あの女用心棒が―
I cannot help but think that the bodyguard
is thinking the same thing I am.
私と同じことを
考えているような気がしてならないのだ
ん？
（シュガ）ヤツも私と同じく―
I believe that she needs to find a fresh
source of information, just as I do.
新たな知識を
必要としているのではないか とな
（チャグム）ハァ ハァ
ハァ ああ…
Are you all right?
（タンダ）大丈夫か？
（タンダ）おぶってやろう
Let me carry you on my back.
Go on, don't be shy.
ほら 遠慮するな
Walk on your own
two feet, Chagum.
（バルサ）自分で歩くんだ チャグム
（チャグム）あ…
It's all right, Balsa. I'm fine.
（タンダ）いいんだ バルサ
俺は大丈夫だから
あんたを背負ったら
誰がタンダの荷物を持つんだい？
If he carries you, who's
going to carry his pack?
トロガイ師かい？
私かい？
Torogai?
Me?
それともタンダが あんたをおぶって
自分の荷物も持つのかい？
Or is Tanda going to carry
both you and his own pack?
（タンダ）
なにも そんな言い方しなくても
Come on, you don't
have to be like that.
Fine, I'll walk on my own.
（チャグム）
分かった 自分で歩く
だから
歩きながらでいいから―
And while we're walking, tell me
about the egg that's inside me.
俺の中に宿っている
卵の事情というのを話してくれ
Tell me what's more important
than my brother dying!
兄上が死んだことよりも
大事な事情というものを！
今は その暇はない
There's no time for that now.
（タンダ）ん？ どうしたんです？
What's the matter?
（トロガイ）うーむ 迷った
We're lost.
（タンダ）そうか トーヤがな
I see. So Toya...
（バルサ）ああ あの子が
体を張ってくれなかったら―
That's right. If he hadn't
risked his life like that...
...I probably wouldn't be
standing here right now.
今頃 私は
ここに いなかったろうよ
遅いな 師匠
Torogai is taking forever.
Well, it's been quite a while
since she last went to Toumi.
師匠もトウミに行くのは
相当 久しぶりだろうからな
（バルサ）違うね
No, that's not it. This is just her way
of showing concern for Chagum.
あれはトロガイ師なりに
チャグムを気遣ったのさ
そうか
I see. Actually, I've been
to Toumi once myself.
俺も一度だけ トウミには
行ったことがあるんだがな―
But I don't remember anything
about how to get there.
でも もう まったく行き方を
覚えていなくってさ
チャグムより小さかったころ―
I was brought there by my uncle when
I was even younger than Chagum.
伯父さんに
連れられて行ったもんだから
That's a shame.
（バルサ）しょうがないね
俺の母方のばあさんが
トウミ村出身でね
My grandmother on my mother's
side came from Toumi village.
Initially, she left Toumi
to marry my grandfather...
最初はトウミから じいさんのところに
嫁に来たんだけど
...but once my mother married into
the family, they both retired to Toumi.
おふくろが嫁いだあとは―
じいさん ともども
トウミに隠とんしたらしいんだ
前に話したか？
（バルサ）いや 今も健在なのかい？
Did I ever tell you about that?
No. Are they still alive?
I'm not sure. Probably not.
どうかな 多分もう…
チャグムには
どう話すつもりなんだ？
How are you planning to tell Chagum?
You know, about the egg-eater...
卵食いのこと
I don't know. It's a touchy subject.
難しいね こればっかりは
Plus, his brother died recently.
お兄さんが
亡くなったとかって話もある
Maybe you should wait until he's had
a chance to come to terms with that.
少し落ち着くまで
待ったほうがいいのかな？
いや どうせ
いずれは話すんだ
No, we'll have to talk to
him about it eventually.
いつまでも黙っていて
いいことはない
This isn't something that
we can keep from him forever.
He'll have to learn the truth
and gain strength from it.
真実を知って自分で
強くなっていくしかないしね
だから トウミに着いて―
So once we reach Toumi and find
some way to fight it, I'll tell him.
何らかの対処方法が
見つかったら話すよ
Rejoice. I found the way through.
（トロガイ）
喜べ 抜け道を見つけた
Also, I found us some food.
それに食い物だ
（ライ）ここを ねぐらにしている
無宿人らが見ていたようです
The vagrants who use this as a
shelter appear to have seen them.
恐らく皇子で間違いないでしょう
It's almost certain
that it was the prince.
うむ そのヤクーの男と老婆も
短槍使いの仲間だろう
Yes. Both that old woman and the
Yakoo man are likely her accomplices.
（モン）うむ…
We just spotted a smoke
signal from Zen and Yun.
たった今 ゼン ユンからの
のろしを確認しました
There doesn't appear to be any sign of
the spear-wielder stopping at Tokal village.
トカル村には短槍使いが
立ち寄った形跡はなかったようです
（ヒョク）他の集落を調べていた
タガとスンからも―
Taga and Sune were
investigating other settlements...
同様の のろしが
...and they sent the same signal.
となると残りはトウミか
In which case,
all that's left is Toumi.
トウミは昔ながらのヤクーの
暮らしが残る数少ない村だと聞く
I've heard that Toumi
is one of the few villages...
...where the ancient Yakoo
ways have been preserved.
よし 我々は先に出かけよう
All right, we will go on ahead.
お待ちください
ここからトウミへは―
Wait a moment, sir.
The terrain between here and Toumi
is difficult by horse, much less on foot.
馬は おろか徒歩でも
分け入るのが困難な地形となります
まずは私とジンが先発します
Jin and I will go on ahead first.
I believe the safest
course of action...
シュガ様は残りの者と合流し―
あとから いらしてくださったほうが
安全かと
...is for you to rendezvous with
the others and follow our lead.
So we can't go by horse?
馬は無理か
分かった では私は
あとから向かう
Very well. I will join you later.
However, even if you
catch sight of the prince...
だが皇子の姿を確認しても―
事に及ぶのは
私の到着を待ってからにしてくれ
...please do not take
any action until I arrive.
女用心棒らに直接
聞いてみたいことがあるのだ
There is something that
I want to ask them in person.
Understood.
We shall do as you wish.
分かりました 仰せのとおりに
Teacher, are you sure
this is a shortcut?
（タンダ）師匠 この道って
本当に近道なんですか？
（トロガイ）これで半日は
稼いだはずじゃ
This should save us half a day.
ペッ まだ早かったか
Still not ripe, huh...
Moribito Guardian of the Spirit
フゥ…
山の天気は変わりやすいですね
Weather in the mountains
sure changes quickly.
なら じきにやむわい
Which means this will
let up soon enough.
There are no traces of them,
but I find that all the more suspicious.
痕跡はないが それが
かえって不自然に思える
（モン）同感だな
I concur.
だが手がかりもない
But there are no
clues to follow, either.
Looks like we'll soon have our
first proper meal in two days.
（トロガイ）おお ２日ぶりに
まともなものが食えそうだ
ああ… チャグムも
腹が減っただろう
You're hungry too,
aren't you, Chagum?
あ… 猿か？
A monkey?
いや 人だ
No, a person.
ハッ！ ハァ ハァ…
Are you from around here?
あんた この辺りの子かい？
あの…
Um...
Are you related to Kunda?
（ニムカ）
あなた クンダさんの？
（タンダ）そうか
I see now. You must
know my grandfather.
君は俺のじいさんのことを
知っているんだね
Yes. Kunda was always
very good to my family...
（ニムカ）はい 私の家族は―
クンダさんにずいぶん
お世話になっていましたから
...so I could tell right away that
you were related to him, Tanda.
それで タンダさんがクンダさんの
家系の方だって すぐに分かったんです
なるほどな
I see. You must look
like your grandfather.
お前は じいさん似ってわけか
By the way,
would that happen to be...
ところで
そいつは もしや？
Oh, this? This is mashira liquor
that I gathered in the mountains.
ああ これは私が
山で集めたマシラ酒です
I knew it!
（トロガイ）やはり そうか！
（タンダ）師匠！
Teacher.
（トロガイ）これは
道切り縄といってな―
This is called a "road's end rope."
ここに つるされたナージの骨を
カラカラと鳴らすことで―
It's a charm where you rattle
the nahji bird bones strung on it...
魔物が入ってくるのを防ぐ
まじないじゃ
...to prevent evil
spirits from entering.
（チャグム）ヨゴの村でも
時折 見かけた
I've seen these in
Yogo villages from time to time.
That's just the Yogo people
imitating Yakoo traditions.
あれはヤクーの風習を
ヨゴ人たちが まねたものだよ
こうやって 村の入り口に
つるしておくのが正しい形なんだ
The proper way to do it is to string it
up across the entrance to a village.
行こう あの丘を越えたところが
トウミ村らしい
Let's go. It looks like Toumi
village is just across that hill.
（トロガイ）まさに
ヨゴ人がやってくる以前の―
It's as if the Yakoo way of life before
the Yogoans arrived is preserved here.
暮らしぶりが
残っているということか
I suppose they don't often
see people like Chagum and me.
さすがに私とチャグムが
珍しいみたいだね
I suppose not.
そのようだな
（ソウヤ）いやあ
よう来られましたな
So good of you to come!
村長(むらおさ)のソウヤです
I'm Soya, the village headman.
It's been many a year since we
last had outsiders visit our village.
外の方が来るなど
何年ぶりのことでしょうか
あんたかい？
クンダさんのお孫さんというのは
Are you him? The one they
say is Kunda's grandson?
You're his spitting image, all right!
確かに よう似とる
（村人たちの笑い声）
だが残念ながらクンダさんは
２年前に亡くなられてしまったが…
I regret to tell you that Kunda
passed away two years ago.
Actually, we didn't come
here to visit my grandfather.
実は俺たちは
じいさんにではなく―
あなたたちの古い知恵を
お借りしたくて来たんです
We hope to gain insight from
your knowledge of the old ways.
We have a lot of questions for
you about the Nyunga Ro Chaga.
ニュンガ･ロ･チャガのことについて
いろいろ伺いたいのです
ん… まあ こんなところで
立ち話をしていても しかたがない
Standing out here talking
won't do any good.
First, please come to my home.
まずは うちに来てくだされ
We'll talk afterwards.
話は それからだ
どうしてまた
そんな大昔のことを聞きに―
Why in the world did you come all this
way to ask about some old legend?
わざわざ おいでに
なられたのですかな？
Well, we're in a bit of
a complicated situation.
（トロガイ）いや なに…
ちょっと込み入った事情があって
できれば ここの語り部に―
If possible, we'd like to ask your
storyteller detailed questions about...
100年前のニュンガ･ロ･イムの
代替わりについて―
...the changing of the Nyunga Ro lm
that happened a hundred years ago.
詳しく話を聞きたいと思ってな
もしや そろそろ水の守り手の
代替わりの時期でしたかな？
Oh, is it almost time again for the
changing of the protector of the waters?
（トロガイ）んっ？ まあな…
Yes, just about.
なら ある意味ちょうどいい
Then, in a sense, you're in luck.
わしの親父(おやじ)の
早死にした兄さんが―
I've heard that my father's
older brother, who died young...
...was a Nyunga Ro Chaga.
ニュンガ･ロ･チャガだったと
聞いています
Is that true?
それは本当ですか？
（ソウヤ）ええ
Yes, but my grandmother was so full
of grief whenever she spoke of him...
ただ わしのばあさんが―
その話をすると
ひどく悲しんだもんで―
あまり詳しくは
覚えておらんのです
...that I don't remember
much in the way of details.
What's more, my mother was
the village's last storyteller.
しかも村の語り部は
わしの母が最後で―
She died last year, so there
is hardly anyone left in the village...
それも昨年
亡くなってしまったから―
この村でもニュンガ･ロ･チャガについて
詳しい話ができる者は―
...who can tell you much about
the Nyunga Ro Chaga now.
もうほとんど おらんのですよ
（一同）えっ
（トロガイ）なぜ語り部の風習を
やめたりした！
Why did you abandon
your storyteller traditions?
あんたも
ご存じとは思うが
As I'm sure you're aware, the training
to become a storyteller is most harsh.
語り部の修行というのは
そりゃ過酷なもんでな
幼いころから朝な夕なに―
From an early age,
you are forced to learn...
幾千もの伝承を
ただひたすら覚え込まされる
...thousands of oral traditions
from sunup to sundown.
It is cruel to force all
that on any one person.
それを１人に押しつけるのは
あまりにも ふびんだし―
わしは そういったことが
あまり好きではなかったので―
I didn't care much for such practices,
so I decided not to appoint a successor.
後継者は
作らんことにしたんです
And besides, we now have the
official history of Shin Yogo to consult.
それに今は建国正史(けんこくせいし)なんてものも
入ってきているので…
Shameful! So this place is no
different from the palace after all.
（トロガイ）なんと！
結局 ここも宮と同じか
（ニムカ）あの…
私 おばあちゃんから
Excuse me...
I heard stories about the Nyunga
Ro Chaga from my grandmother...
ニュンガ･ロ･チャガの話
聞いているから―
...so I think I can tell
you a few of them.
いくらかなら話せると思うけど…
（一同）えっ
（ソウヤ）そういや お前
ヤマビメ持っちゃ―
Come to think of it, you used to visit my
mother carrying yamabime, didn't you?
おふくろのところに
遊びに行ってたっけなあ
Anything you can tell us
would be appreciated.
（バルサ）どんなことでもいい
おばあさんから聞いたことを
話してくれるかい？
Can you tell us what you
heard from your grandmother?
Yes.
おばあちゃんが言うには―
According to my grandmother...
ひいおじいちゃんの
早くに死んだお兄さんの体に―
...in the body of my great-grandfather's
older brother, the one who died young...
ある日突然 ニュンガ･ロ･イムの
卵が入ったんだって
...the egg of Nyunga Ro Im
suddenly appeared.
Nyunga Ro lm is a spirit who lives
deep underwater in Nayug's seas...
ニュンガ･ロ･イムはナユグの
深い水の底に住む精霊で―
大きな貝みたいな姿をしているの
...and is shaped
like a giant shellfish.
The life force from its mouth becomes
clouds in Sagu and creates rain.
口から吐き出す精気は
サグの雲になって雨を作る
But once every hundred years,
Nyunga Ro lm lays an egg and dies.
でもニュンガ･ロ･イムは
100年に１度―
卵を産んで死んでしまう…
When that happens,
the clouds vanish from the skies...
そうすると今度は
空から雲が消えていって―
...and we experience
a period of dry weather.
日照りが続くようになる
She said we have cared for the
guardian of the spirit since ancient times...
だから次の精霊の卵が
無事かえるように―
ヤクーは大昔から精霊の守り人を
大事にしたんだって
...so that the egg of the
next spirit would hatch safely.
But that is usually only
until the egg matures.
でも普通 それは
卵が育つまでで―
When the time comes for
Nyunga Ro lm's egg to hatch...
精霊の守り人は―
ニュンガ･ロ･イムの
卵が かえる時期になると―
たった１人で
宴(うたげ)の地に行ってしまい―
...the guardian travels alone to the
land of feasting, never to be seen again.
二度と帰ってこないの
Overcome with grief,
my great-grandmother's mother...
ひいおじいちゃんのお母さんは
それが悲しくて悲しくて―
村の人に お願いして―
...begged the people of the village
to help protect her son as well...
精霊の守り人になった
自分の子供も―
一緒に守ってもらうことにしたんだって
...as he had become
a guardian of the spirit.
その話は
わしも覚えているなあ
You know, I remember
hearing about that myself.
Master Shuga, it's a
signal from the commander.
シュガ様
お頭からの合図です
どうやら あの方向に進むのが
近道のようです
It looks like there is
a shortcut in that direction.
I see.
そうか あの先がトウミか
And beyond it lies Toumi.
So, what did the villagers do
with the Nyunga Ro Chaga?
（タンダ）
で そのニュンガ･ロ･チャガを―
村の人は どうしたんだい？
When the spring day
of equality drew near...
春の等しき日が近づくと
ニュンガ･ロ･チャガは―
...the Nyunga Ro Chaga left the village
like a bird beginning its migration.
まるで鳥が渡りを始めるように
村を出―
大人たちも そのあとを追って
長い旅に出た
The adult villagers
followed him on his long journey.
At long last, they reached a large spring
at the headwaters of the Aoyumi River...
そして青弓川(あおゆみがわ)の水源―
シグ･サルアの咲き乱れる
大きな泉に着いた
...where the shigu salua
bloomed everywhere.
There, the guardian of the spirit
prepared to return the egg to Nayug.
精霊の守り人は そこで
卵をナユグに返す準備に入った
But Rarunga had also come
to this spring from Nayug.
だけど そこには
鳥の卵を狙う蛇のように―
Like an egg-eating snake striking its prey,
Rarunga attacked the Nyunga Ro Chaga.
ニュンガ･ロ･チャガを狙って―
ラルンガもナユグから
やってきていた
And before the eyes
of the watching adults...
そして大人たちが
見ている目の前で―
...using enormous claws that could
be neither seen nor felt by humans...
人には見ることも
触ることもできない大きな爪で―
ニュンガ･ロ･チャガを
真っ二つに引き裂いてしまったの
...it ripped the
Nyunga Ro Chaga in two.
ああっ！ ハァッ ハァッ
（バルサ）ハッ
俺も そうやって死ぬのか？
Am I... Am I going to die
like that too, Balsa?
バルサ… あ…
死ぬって いったい その子は？
Die like what?
Who in the world is this child?
実は この子が今度の
ニュンガ･ロ･チャガなのです
The fact is, this boy is
the current Nyunga Ro Chaga.
As I sat huddled and alone, holding back the tears on those nights...
When it felt like I was about to succumb to my doubts...
...there you were, at my side before I knew it.
It was none other than you who was there for me.
I keep wishing, "I want to be strong." I stumble and hurt myself again.
But because I have you to believe in, I can get back to my feet.
I simply want to tell my dear one, "Thank you."
At the top of my lungs, again and again.
I call out to my precious loved one.
Is my voice reaching you?
In this world that always changes, human warmth never does.
I'm certain I sensed the presence of the one that I hold dear.
～♪
Next Time
It is when they are beaten down by
fate that people reveal their true selves.
They become distressed, angry,
and then they cross paths.
Next time, "Escape."
Episode
19 Escape
Balsa wields her weapon
filled with determination.